Drake Hopkins

Lakeland, FL | drakehopkins@outlook.com | drakeafk.jo | GitHub | LinkedIn

Summary

Web Developer & IT Professional with 4+ years of successful industry experience. I have built many websites and web applications as well as held roles performing a variety of IT related tasks. I currently specialize in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, but constantly learning and practicing with different technologies. I also have experience working with Bootstrap, Svelte & SvelteKit, and other languages/environments including NodeJS, Python, and Rust. Feel free to visit my personal website to view samples of my work and more.

Experience

Web Developer - DAFK (Freelance)

08/2019 - Present

- Design and develop websites for individuals and small businesses
- Utilize HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and a variety frameworks/libraries/environments including NodeJS, Svelte & SvelteKit, Astro, TailwindCSS, and Bootstrap (Plus brief backend work with Python and Rust)
- Manage multiple projects simultaneously

IT Consultant – City Government

11/2022 – 06/2023

- Install and configure devices, hardware, and applications
- Troubleshoot hardware, software, and network problems
- Implement new IT systems and update infrastructure

IT Support (Intern) – Farmers Elevator

04/2016 - 03/2019

- Setup and maintain Windows and Linux systems
- Form data backup and disaster recovery plans
- Network troubleshooting

MISC Experience

English Language Tutor – Freelance

07/2022 - 05/2023

- Tutor students learning English as a second language
- Design and implement plans and procedures for students to meet their English language goals
- Work with students internationally at varying ages and educational levels

Education

Arkansas State University

08/2014 - 05/2019

Bachelor of Arts in Political Science

- Completed many different courses outside of degree requirements in various academic disciplines:
 - Mathematics; Computer Science; Biology; Chemistry;

Certifications

- Google IT Support; Google IT Automation with Python; Systems Administration and IT Infrastructure Services; CompTIA A+;
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures; Responsive Web Design; Complete WebDev Bootcamp;
- 120-Hour TESOL/TEFL (Teaching English as a Foreign Language)

Skills

- Windows (8/10/11); Linux (Ubuntu, Arch, Kali); macOS; iOS; iPadOS; Android;
- Desktops; Laptops; Printers and Scanners; Routers; Modems; Switches; Mobile Devices;
- Microsoft Office; Google Workspace; Adobe Creative Cloud/Suite;
- Active Directory; PowerShell / Terminal; SSH; VPN; Remote Desktop;
- Google Cloud Platform
- HTML; CSS; JavaScript; NodeJS; Svelte and SvelteKit; Astro TailwindCSS; Bootstrap; Python;
- Communication; Analytical; Problem Solving; Organization; Attention to Detail;